<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.8.17">
  <compounddef id="classHypothesesTree" kind="class" language="C++" prot="public">
    <compoundname>HypothesesTree</compoundname>
    <includes refid="HypothesesTree_8h" local="no">HypothesesTree.h</includes>
    <briefdescription>
    </briefdescription>
    <detaileddescription>
<para><ref refid="HypothesesTree_8h" kindref="compound">HypothesesTree.h</ref></para>
<para>The hypothesis tree class is used to store all hypotheses. Protected members are trailed with an underscore. Each time a new measurement arrives, the tree is expanded and the most hypothesis with the maximum a posteriori probability (MAP) is selected. The MAP hypothesis is believed to represent the current state of the world. The number of hypotheses in a tree grows more than exponential with the number of measurement and, therefore, this class includes a pruning function that after each measurement prunes the least probable hypotheses. A hypotheses tree contains:<itemizedlist>
<listitem><para>a multiset containing pointers to all hypotheses</para>
</listitem><listitem><para>a list containing pointers to all objects that exist in all hypotheses</para>
</listitem><listitem><para>a pointer to the MAP hypothesis</para>
</listitem></itemizedlist>
</para>
<para><simplesect kind="authors"><para>Jos Elfring, Sjoerd van den Dries </para>
</simplesect>
<simplesect kind="date"><para>March, 2011 </para>
</simplesect>
<simplesect kind="version"><para>1.0</para>
</simplesect>
<hruler/>
</para>
<para>This file is part of the RoboEarth ROS world modeling package.</para>
<para>It was originally created for <ulink url="http://www.roboearth.org/">RoboEarth</ulink>. The research leading to these results has received funding from the European Union Seventh Framework Programme FP7/2007-2013 under grant agreement no248942 RoboEarth.</para>
<para>Copyright (C) 2011 by <ulink url=" mailto:J.Elfring@tue.nl">Jos Elfring</ulink> and <ulink url=" mailto:S.v.d.Dries@tue.nl">Sjoerd van den Dries</ulink>, Eindhoven University of Technology</para>
<para>Redistribution and use in source and binary forms, with or without modification, are permitted provided that the following conditions are met:</para>
<para><itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<para>Redistributions of source code must retain the above copyright notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer. </para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>Redistributions in binary form must reproduce the above copyright notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer in the documentation and/or other materials provided with the distribution. </para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>Neither the name of Willow Garage, Inc. nor the names of its contributors may be used to endorse or promote products derived from this software without specific prior written permission. </para>
</listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</para>
<para>THIS SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED BY THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS AND CONTRIBUTORS &quot;AS IS&quot; AND ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE ARE DISCLAIMED. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE COPYRIGHT OWNER OR CONTRIBUTORS BE LIABLE FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES (INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES; LOSS OF USE, DATA, OR PROFITS; OR BUSINESS INTERRUPTION) HOWEVER CAUSED AND ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, WHETHER IN CONTRACT, STRICT LIABILITY, OR TORT (INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE OR OTHERWISE) ARISING IN ANY WAY OUT OF THE USE OF THIS SOFTWARE, EVEN IF ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE.</para>
<para><image type="html" name="RoboEarth.org_logo.gif"></image>
 <image type="latex" name="RoboEarth.org_logo.gif"></image>
</para>
<para><simplesect kind="authors"><para>Jos Elfring, Sjoerd van den Dries </para>
</simplesect>
<simplesect kind="date"><para>March, 2011 </para>
</simplesect>
<simplesect kind="version"><para>1.0 </para>
</simplesect>
</para>
    </detaileddescription>
    <location file="include/wire/logic/HypothesesTree.h" line="2" column="1"/>
    <listofallmembers>
    </listofallmembers>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
